{
    "id": "4fe00258ee7d4bd3b8be41f864a8c66c",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What you did …………………. wrong.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the noun clause 'what you did'. When the subject is a clause, the verb is singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "have been"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Walk carefully lest you ………………….. slip.",
            "description": "Should is the only auxiliary that can be used after lest. ",
            "answers": [
                "may",
                "would",
                "should"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I was not invited …………………….. her birthday party.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "for",
                "of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If he had received medical attention in time, he ………………………",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will survive",
                "would survive",
                "would have survived"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following words does not have a plural form?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "bat",
                "bear",
                "equipment",
                "vehicle"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Trespassing is prohibited. Here trespassing is a ………………….",
            "description": "When an -ing form is used as a subject, it is a gerund.",
            "answers": [
                "participle",
                "infinitive",
                "gerund"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He stood …………………… the gate.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "before",
                "beside",
                "besides",
                "in front of"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody came, ……………………?",
            "description": "Use an affirmative tag after negative expressions like nobody and hardly.",
            "answers": [
                "did anybody",
                "did they",
                "didn't they"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither the manager nor his secretary ……………………. present.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were",
                "has"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "To smell a rat is to ………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "feel a foul smell",
                "suspect deception",
                "spread rumors"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Send this letter by registered post. Change into passive",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Letter be sent by registered post",
                "Let this letter be sent by registered post",
                "Letter should be spent by registered post"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My father ………………… at 30 every day.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is waking up",
                "wakes up",
                "woke up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}